<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vulnerability xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" Lang="INTL" Vul_ID="RHSA-2015-0535" Revision="3" CVE_ID="CVE-2014-7300">
  <Status>Deleted</Status>
  <Groups />
  <DependsOn />
  <Patches>
    <Patch UniqueFilename="*gnome-shell-browser-plugin-3.8.4-45.el7.x86_64.rpm" Hash="" Silent="CRSNo" Reboot="RNo" Download="DManual">
      <Name>gnome-shell-browser-plugin-3.8.4-45.el7.x86_64.rpm</Name>
      <Comments />
      <URL />
      <State>Enabled</State>
      <Files>
        <File>
          <Path>gnome-shell-browser-plugin::x86_64</Path>
          <FileDate>0001-01-01T00:00:00.0000000+00:00</FileDate>
          <FileSize>0</FileSize>
          <Checksum>e4ef65b63ecf30d8142157d39718f338</Checksum>
          <Version>3.8.4-45.el7</Version>
          <CommandID>e</CommandID>
          <Flags>P</Flags>
        </File>
      </Files>
      <RegKeys />
      <Products>
        <ID>35551</ID>
      </Products>
      <Platforms>
        <ID>rhel7_x86_64</ID>
      </Platforms>
      <CustVars />
      <Cmds>
        <Cmd Type="shellscript">
          <Args>
            <Arg N="scriptcode" V="#!/bin/bash&#xA;&#xA;function updatepk()&#xA;{&#xA; if [ ! -z $1 ]; then&#xA;   if [ -e /var/run/yum.pid ];then &#xA;    exit 10  &#xA;   fi&#xA;   result=`yum -y update $1 2&gt;&amp;1` &#xA;   status=$? &#xA;   commandexist=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;yum: command not found&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$commandexist&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 8&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;    commandexist=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;yum: No such file or directory&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$commandexist&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 8&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   islock=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;lock /var/run/yum.pid&quot;`&#xA;   &#xA;   if [ &quot;$islock&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 10&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   islock=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;/var/run/yum.pid: another copy is running&quot;`&#xA;   &#xA;   if [ &quot;$islock&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 10&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;There was an error communicating with RHN&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;This system is not registered with RHN&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;    isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;No Repositories Available to Set Up&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;    isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;Error Class Code: 9 Error Class Info: Invalid System Credentials&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;    isscriptletfailed=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;error:&quot; | grep -E &quot;scriptlet failed, exit status 255&quot;`&#xA;    if [ &quot;$isscriptletfailed&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 6&#xA;   fi&#xA;   if [ $status -ne 0 ];then&#xA;     exit 7&#xA;   fi &#xA; fi&#xA;}&#xA;updatepk gnome-shell-browser-plugin  &#xA;&#xA;exit 0" />
          </Args>
        </Cmd>
      </Cmds>
    </Patch>
  </Patches>
  <PublishDate>2015-03-05T00:00:00.0000000+00:00</PublishDate>
  <Title>Low: GNOME Shell security, bug fix, and enhancement update</Title>
  <Description>Updated gnome-shell, mutter, clutter, and cogl packages that fix one security 
 issue, several bugs, and add one enhancement are now available for Red Hat 
 Enterprise Linux 7. 
 
 Red Hat Product Security has rated this update as having Low security impact. A 
 Common Vulnerability Scoring System (CVSS) base score, which gives a detailed 
 severity rating, is available from the CVE link in the References section. 
 GNOME Shell and the packages it depends upon provide the core user interface of 
 the Red Hat Enterprise Linux desktop, including functions such as navigating 
 between windows and launching applications. 
 
 It was found that the GNOME shell did not disable the Print Screen key when the 
 screen was locked. This could allow an attacker with physical access to a system 
 with a locked screen to crash the screen-locking application by creating a large 
 amount of screenshots. (CVE-2014-7300) 
 
 This update also fixes the following bugs: 
 
 * The Timed Login feature, which automatically logs in a specified user after a 
 specified period of time, stopped working after the first user of the GUI logged 
 out. This has been fixed, and the specified user is always logged in if no one 
 else logs in. (BZ#1043571) 
 
 * If two monitors were arranged vertically with the secondary monitor above the 
 primary monitor, it was impossible to move windows onto the secondary monitor. 
 With this update, windows can be moved through the upper edge of the first 
 monitor to the secondary monitor. (BZ#1075240) 
 
 * If the Gnome Display Manager (GDM) user list was disabled and a user entered 
 the user name, the password prompt did not appear. Instead, the user had to 
 enter the user name one more time. The GDM code that contained this error has 
 been fixed, and users can enter their user names and passwords as expected. 
 (BZ#1109530) 
 
 * Prior to this update, only a small area was available on the GDM login screen 
 for a custom text banner. As a consequence, when a long banner was used, it did 
 not fit into the area, and the person reading the banner had to use scrollbars 
 to view the whole text. With this update, more space is used for the banner if 
 necessary, which allows the user to read the message conveniently. (BZ#1110036) 
 
 * When the Cancel button was pressed while an LDAP user name and password was 
 being validated, the GDM code did not handle the situation correctly. As a 
 consequence, GDM became unresponsive, and it was impossible to return to the 
 login screen. The affected code has been fixed, and LDAP user validation can be 
 canceled, allowing another user to log in instead. (BZ#1137041) 
 
 * If the window focus mode in GNOME was set to "mouse" or "sloppy", navigating 
 through areas of a pop-up menu displayed outside its parent window caused the 
 window to lose its focus. Consequently, the menu was not usable. This has been 
 fixed, and the window focus is kept in under this scenario. (BZ#1149585) 
 
 * If user authentication is configured to require a smart card to log in, user 
 names are obtained from the smart card. The authentication is then performed by 
 entering the smart card PIN. Prior to this update, the login screen allowed a 
 user name to be entered if no smart card was inserted, but due to a bug in the 
 underlying code, the screen became unresponsive. If, on the other hand, a smart 
 card was used for authentication, the user was logged in as soon as the 
 authentication was complete. As a consequence, it was impossible to select a 
 session other than GNOME Classic. Both of these problems have been fixed. Now, a 
 smart card is required when this type of authentication is enabled, and any 
 other installed session can be selected by the user. (BZ#1159385, BZ#1163474) 
 
 In addition, this update adds the following enhancement: 
 
 * Support for quad-buffer OpenGL stereo visuals has been added. As a result, 
 OpenGL applications that use quad-buffer stereo can be run and properly 
 displayed within the GNOME desktop when used with a video driver and hardware 
 with the necessary capabilities. (BZ#861507, BZ#1108890, BZ#1108891, BZ#1108893) 
 
 All GNOME Shell users are advised to upgrade to these updated packages, which 
 contain backported patches to correct these issues and add this enhancement. 
 
 Note for remediation: Please disable the SELinux for RHEL 4/5 when repairing, or some rpm packages will fail to install.</Description>
  <Severity>4</Severity>
  <Vendor>Redhat</Vendor>
  <MoreInfoURL>https://rhn.redhat.com/errata/RHSA-2015-0535.html</MoreInfoURL>
  <FAQURL />
</Vulnerability>