<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vulnerability xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" Lang="INTL" Vul_ID="RHBA-2015-0289" Revision="1" CVE_ID="">
  <Status>Enabled</Status>
  <Patches>
    <Patch UniqueFilename="*virtio-win-1.7.3-1.el7.noarch.rpm" Silent="CRSNo" Reboot="RNo" Download="DManual">
      <Name>virtio-win-1.7.3-1.el7.noarch.rpm</Name>
      <Comments />
      <URL />
      <State>Enabled</State>
      <Files>
        <File>
          <Path>virtio-win::noarch</Path>
          <FileDate>0001-01-01T00:00:00.0000000</FileDate>
          <FileSize>0</FileSize>
          <Checksum>b549825212f2b6dbd6698b98e514d412db2488cd01c91a204b1d2dcfab8018d3</Checksum>
          <Version>1.7.3-1.el7</Version>
          <CommandID>e</CommandID>
          <Flags>P</Flags>
        </File>
      </Files>
      <Products>
        <ID>32525</ID>
      </Products>
      <Platforms>
        <ID>rhel7_x86_64</ID>
      </Platforms>
      <CustVars />
      <Cmds>
        <Cmd Type="shellscript">
          <Args>
            <Arg N="scriptcode" V="#!/bin/bash&#xA;&#xA;function updatepk()&#xA;{&#xA; if [ ! -z $1 ]; then&#xA;   if [ -e /var/run/yum.pid ];then &#xA;    exit 10  &#xA;   fi&#xA;   result=`yum -y update $1 2&gt;&amp;1` &#xA;   status=$? &#xA;   commandexist=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;yum: command not found&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$commandexist&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 8&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;    commandexist=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;yum: No such file or directory&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$commandexist&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 8&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   islock=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;lock /var/run/yum.pid&quot;`&#xA;   &#xA;   if [ &quot;$islock&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 10&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   islock=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;/var/run/yum.pid: another copy is running&quot;`&#xA;   &#xA;   if [ &quot;$islock&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 10&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;There was an error communicating with RHN&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;This system is not registered with RHN&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;    isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;No Repositories Available to Set Up&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;    isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;Error Class Code: 9 Error Class Info: Invalid System Credentials&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;    isscriptletfailed=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;error:&quot; | grep -E &quot;scriptlet failed, exit status 255&quot;`&#xA;    if [ &quot;$isscriptletfailed&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 6&#xA;   fi&#xA;   if [ $status -ne 0 ];then&#xA;     exit 7&#xA;   fi &#xA; fi&#xA;}&#xA;updatepk virtio-win  &#xA;&#xA;exit 0" />
          </Args>
        </Cmd>
      </Cmds>
    </Patch>
  </Patches>
  <PublishDate>2014-10-02T00:00:00.0000000</PublishDate>
  <Title>virtio-win bug fix and enhancement update</Title>
  <Description>
        
The virtio-win package provides paravirtualized network drivers for most Microsoft Windows operating systems. Paravirtualized drivers are virtualization-aware drivers used by fully virtualized guests running on Red Hat Enterprise Linux. Fully virtualized guests using the paravirtualized drivers gain significantly better I/O performance than fully virtualized guests running without the drivers. 
The virtio-win package has been upgraded to upstream version 1.7.3, which provides a number of bug fixes and enhancements over the previous version. (BZ#1178458)
This update also fixes the following bugs:
 An error in the underlying code previously caused the mouse pointer to become deactivated during the installation of the virtio-serial driver on Windows XP and Windows Server 2003 systems. This update includes a more recent version of the virtio-serial driver, which fixes this problem. (BZ#1048996)
 Previously, the Windows Server 2008 virtio-rng drivers were not supported on Red Hat Enterprise Linux systems because the "Verify WDF Coinstaller Version for KMDF" job failed on Windows Server 2008 guests. This update fixes the problem with the mentioned job, and Windows Server 2008 virtio-rng drivers are now fully supported. (BZ#1080251)
 The "Manufacturer" strings in the driver properties information for the virtio-win drivers have been corrected to be uniform and up-to-date. In addition, the name of the WDF Coinstaller .dll file has been made more consistent. (BZ#1090832, BZ#1139509)
In addition, this update adds the following enhancements:
 The "guest-set-time" command has been added to virtio-win, which allows users to synchronize the system time of a guest after it was suspended and then resumed. (BZ#1157918)
 In order to support Windows Server 2012 and Windows Driver Kit 8.1, virtio-win drivers are now built with Microsoft Visual Studio 2013. (BZ#1051886)
Users of virtio-win are advised to upgrade to this updated package, which fixes these bugs and adds these enhancements.
        Note for remediation: Please disable the SELinux for RHEL 4/5 when repairing, or some rpm packages will fail to install.</Description>
  <Severity>5</Severity>
  <Vendor>Redhat</Vendor>
  <MoreInfoURL>https://access.redhat.com/errata/RHBA-2015:0289</MoreInfoURL>
  <FAQURL />
</Vulnerability>