<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vulnerability xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" Lang="INTL" Vul_ID="RHBA-2015-2118" Revision="1" CVE_ID="">
  <Status>Enabled</Status>
  <Patches>
    <Patch UniqueFilename="*sos-3.2-35.el7.noarch.rpm" Silent="CRSNo" Reboot="RNo" Download="DManual">
      <Name>sos-3.2-35.el7.noarch.rpm</Name>
      <Comments />
      <URL />
      <State>Enabled</State>
      <Files>
        <File>
          <Path>sos::noarch</Path>
          <FileDate>0001-01-01T00:00:00.0000000</FileDate>
          <FileSize>0</FileSize>
          <Checksum>74af5754711bf93f2b7e30adcb1b9ead63fd0dde75251aa861c36a391f59135b</Checksum>
          <Version>3.2-35.el7</Version>
          <CommandID>e</CommandID>
          <Flags>P</Flags>
        </File>
      </Files>
      <Products>
        <ID>38341</ID>
      </Products>
      <Platforms>
        <ID>rhel7_x86_64</ID>
      </Platforms>
      <CustVars />
      <Cmds>
        <Cmd Type="shellscript">
          <Args>
            <Arg N="scriptcode" V="#!/bin/bash&#xA;&#xA;function updatepk()&#xA;{&#xA; if [ ! -z $1 ]; then&#xA;   if [ -e /var/run/yum.pid ];then &#xA;    exit 10  &#xA;   fi&#xA;   result=`yum -y update $1 2&gt;&amp;1` &#xA;   status=$? &#xA;   commandexist=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;yum: command not found&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$commandexist&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 8&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;    commandexist=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;yum: No such file or directory&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$commandexist&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 8&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   islock=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;lock /var/run/yum.pid&quot;`&#xA;   &#xA;   if [ &quot;$islock&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 10&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   islock=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;/var/run/yum.pid: another copy is running&quot;`&#xA;   &#xA;   if [ &quot;$islock&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 10&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;There was an error communicating with RHN&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;This system is not registered with RHN&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;    isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;No Repositories Available to Set Up&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;    isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;Error Class Code: 9 Error Class Info: Invalid System Credentials&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;    isscriptletfailed=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;error:&quot; | grep -E &quot;scriptlet failed, exit status 255&quot;`&#xA;    if [ &quot;$isscriptletfailed&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 6&#xA;   fi&#xA;   if [ $status -ne 0 ];then&#xA;     exit 7&#xA;   fi &#xA; fi&#xA;}&#xA;updatepk sos  &#xA;&#xA;exit 0" />
          </Args>
        </Cmd>
      </Cmds>
    </Patch>
  </Patches>
  <PublishDate>2015-11-19T00:00:00.0000000</PublishDate>
  <Title>sos bug fix and enhancement update</Title>
  <Description>
        
The sos package contains a set of utilities that gather information from system hardware, logs, and configuration files. The information can then be used for diagnostic purposes and debugging.
This update fixes the following bugs:
 Various OpenStack plug-ins for the sosreport utility were collecting passwords in plain text. As a consequence, the compressed file created after using sosreport could contain human-readable passwords. This update adds obfuscation of all passwords to sosreport OpenStack plug-ins, and the affected passwords in the sosreport tarball are no longer human-readable. (BZ#1243092, BZ#1240666)
 When using sosreport in interactive mode, the "--name" and "--ticket-number" command-line options did not have any effect. As a consequence, the default option values in interactive sosreport prompts were not updated with the provided options. Now, "--name" and "--ticket-number" work as expected, and when either of them is provided in sosreport's interactive mode, the interactive prompts reflect it accordingly. (BZ#1185093)
 The cluster plug-in incorrectly created a directory for the destination path used by the crm_report utility. As a consequence, crm_report failed because the existing directory and its output was not collected. Now, the cluster plug-in does not create the directory for crm_report and lets crm_report create it by itself. As a result, the cluster plug-in collects crm_report output as expected. (BZ#1200526)
 Using the sosreport tool did not generate an HTML report even when the "--no-report" option was not used. The default value of "--no-report" has been set correctly, which ensures that sosreport generates the HTML report unless "--no-report" is used. (BZ#1219720)
 When using the sosreport tool on an OpenStack Neutron node, the openstack_neutron plug-in for the sos utility failed to collect data from the OpenStack Networking service. With this update, the condition detecting Neutron and Quantum client installations has been adjusted to be more accurate, and openstack_neutron now collects Neutron data reliably.
(BZ#1213315)
 The ovirt plug-in for the sos utility did not properly obfuscate the passwords in the ovirt-engine setup answer file, and the passwords were thus collected in plain text. With this update, the passwords are now obfuscated as intended, and no longer collected. (BZ#1162788)
 Under certain circumstances, the hpasm plug-in for the sos utility became unresponsive and collected no data. This update disables the timeout when calling sosreport with the hpasm plug-in, and hpasm no longer becomes unresponsive. (BZ#1214209)
In addition, this update adds the following enhancements:
 The foreman plug-in has been extended. It newly generates foreman-debug for Satellite 6, thus allowing users to gather details about Satellite 6 system environment. (BZ#1135317)
 The sosreport tool has been enhanced in a number of ways that allow it to run in a super-privileged container (SPC) in order to be able to inspect the containing host. (BZ#1185990)
 The chrony plug-in has been added to the sos package. The plug-in captures configuration data and command outputs from the Chrony network time protocol, and thus allows users to gather information about the chrony package environment. (BZ#1165418)
 The sosreport tool is now able to collect process-related information from various applications, including ptp, lastlog, and ethtool. As a part of this change, the "startup" plug-in has been renamed to "services" in order to better communicate its function. (BZ#1195087)
 The saphana, sapnw, and vhostmd plug-ins have been added to the sos package. The plug-ins capture various configuration data and logs and command outputs from SAP Hana and SAP NetWeaver, and thus allow users to gather details about the SAP Hana and SAP NetWeaver system environment. (BZ#1195608)
        Note for remediation: Please disable the SELinux for RHEL 4/5 when repairing, or some rpm packages will fail to install.</Description>
  <Severity>5</Severity>
  <Vendor>Redhat</Vendor>
  <MoreInfoURL>https://access.redhat.com/errata/RHBA-2015:2118</MoreInfoURL>
  <FAQURL />
</Vulnerability>