<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vulnerability xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" Lang="INTL" Vul_ID="RHSA-2015-0102" Revision="5" CVE_ID="CVE-2014-4171,CVE-2014-5471,CVE-2014-5472,CVE-2014-7145,CVE-2014-7822,CVE-2014-7841">
  <Status>Deleted</Status>
  <Groups />
  <DependsOn />
  <Patches>
    <Patch UniqueFilename="*kernel-doc-3.10.0-123.20.1.el7.noarch.rpm" Hash="" Silent="CRSNo" Reboot="RNo" Download="DManual">
      <Name>kernel-doc-3.10.0-123.20.1.el7.noarch.rpm</Name>
      <Comments />
      <URL />
      <State>Enabled</State>
      <Files>
        <File>
          <Path>kernel-doc::noarch</Path>
          <FileDate>0001-01-01T00:00:00.0000000+00:00</FileDate>
          <FileSize>0</FileSize>
          <Checksum>60a9a2750cd40c8c38e876a757ba60a2</Checksum>
          <Version>3.10.0-123.20.1.el7</Version>
          <CommandID>e</CommandID>
          <Flags>P</Flags>
        </File>
      </Files>
      <RegKeys />
      <Products>
        <ID>33152</ID>
      </Products>
      <Platforms>
        <ID>rhel7_x86_64</ID>
      </Platforms>
      <CustVars />
      <Cmds>
        <Cmd Type="shellscript">
          <Args>
            <Arg N="scriptcode" V="#!/bin/bash&#xA;&#xA;function updatepk()&#xA;{&#xA; if [ ! -z $1 ]; then&#xA;   if [ -e /var/run/yum.pid ];then &#xA;    exit 10  &#xA;   fi&#xA;   result=`yum -y update $1 2&gt;&amp;1` &#xA;   status=$? &#xA;   commandexist=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;yum: command not found&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$commandexist&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 8&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;    commandexist=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;yum: No such file or directory&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$commandexist&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 8&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   islock=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;lock /var/run/yum.pid&quot;`&#xA;   &#xA;   if [ &quot;$islock&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 10&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   islock=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;/var/run/yum.pid: another copy is running&quot;`&#xA;   &#xA;   if [ &quot;$islock&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 10&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;There was an error communicating with RHN&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;This system is not registered with RHN&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;    isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;No Repositories Available to Set Up&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;    isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;Error Class Code: 9 Error Class Info: Invalid System Credentials&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;    isscriptletfailed=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;error:&quot; | grep -E &quot;scriptlet failed, exit status 255&quot;`&#xA;    if [ &quot;$isscriptletfailed&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 6&#xA;   fi&#xA;   if [ $status -ne 0 ];then&#xA;     exit 7&#xA;   fi &#xA; fi&#xA;}&#xA;updatepk kernel-doc  &#xA;&#xA;exit 0" />
          </Args>
        </Cmd>
      </Cmds>
    </Patch>
  </Patches>
  <PublishDate>2015-01-28T00:00:00.0000000+00:00</PublishDate>
  <Title>Important: kernel security and bug fix update</Title>
  <Description>Updated kernel packages that fix multiple security issues and several bugs 
 are now available for Red Hat Enterprise Linux 7. 
 
 Red Hat Product Security has rated this update as having Important security 
 impact. Common Vulnerability Scoring System (CVSS) base scores, which give 
 detailed severity ratings, are available for each vulnerability from the 
 CVE links in the References section. 
 The kernel packages contain the Linux kernel, the core of any Linux 
 operating system. 
 
 * A flaw was found in the way the Linux kernel's SCTP implementation 
 validated INIT chunks when performing Address Configuration Change 
 (ASCONF). A remote attacker could use this flaw to crash the system by 
 sending a specially crafted SCTP packet to trigger a NULL pointer 
 dereference on the system. (CVE-2014-7841, Important) 
 
 * A race condition flaw was found in the way the Linux kernel's mmap(2), 
 madvise(2), and fallocate(2) system calls interacted with each other while 
 operating on virtual memory file system files. A local user could use this 
 flaw to cause a denial of service. (CVE-2014-4171, Moderate) 
 
 * A NULL pointer dereference flaw was found in the way the Linux kernel's 
 Common Internet File System (CIFS) implementation handled mounting of file 
 system shares. A remote attacker could use this flaw to crash a client 
 system that would mount a file system share from a malicious server. 
 (CVE-2014-7145, Moderate) 
 
 * A flaw was found in the way the Linux kernel's splice() system call 
 validated its parameters. On certain file systems, a local, unprivileged 
 user could use this flaw to write past the maximum file size, and thus 
 crash the system. (CVE-2014-7822, Moderate) 
 
 * It was found that the parse_rock_ridge_inode_internal() function of the 
 Linux kernel's ISOFS implementation did not correctly check relocated 
 directories when processing Rock Ridge child link (CL) tags. An attacker 
 with physical access to the system could use a specially crafted ISO image 
 to crash the system or, potentially, escalate their privileges on the 
 system. (CVE-2014-5471, CVE-2014-5472, Low) 
 
 Red Hat would like to thank Akira Fujita of NEC for reporting the 
 CVE-2014-7822 issue. The CVE-2014-7841 issue was discovered by Liu Wei of 
 Red Hat. 
 
 This update also fixes the following bugs: 
 
 * Previously, a kernel panic could occur if a process reading from a locked 
 NFS file was killed and the lock was not released properly before the read 
 operations finished. Consequently, the system crashed. The code handling 
 file locks has been fixed, and instead of halting, the system now emits a 
 warning about the unreleased lock. (BZ#1172266) 
 
 * A race condition in the command abort handling logic of the ipr device 
 driver could cause the kernel to panic when the driver received a response 
 to an abort command prior to receiving other responses to the aborted 
 command due to the support for multiple interrupts. With this update, the 
 abort handler waits for the aborted command's responses first before 
 completing an abort operation. (BZ#1162734) 
 
 * Previously, a race condition could occur when changing a Page Table Entry 
 (PTE) or a Page Middle Directory (PMD) to "pte_numa" or "pmd_numa", 
 respectively, causing the kernel to crash. This update removes the BUG_ON() 
 macro from the __handle_mm_fault() function, preventing the kernel panic in 
 the aforementioned scenario. (BZ#1170662) 
 
 All kernel users are advised to upgrade to these updated packages, which 
 contain backported patches to correct these issues. The system must be 
 rebooted for this update to take effect. 
 
 Note for remediation: Please disable the SELinux for RHEL 4/5 when repairing, or some rpm packages will fail to install.</Description>
  <Severity>2</Severity>
  <Vendor>Redhat</Vendor>
  <MoreInfoURL>https://rhn.redhat.com/errata/RHSA-2015-0102.html</MoreInfoURL>
  <FAQURL />
</Vulnerability>