<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Vulnerability xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" Lang="INTL" Vul_ID="RHBA-2015-0295" Revision="1" CVE_ID="">
  <Status>Enabled</Status>
  <Patches>
    <Patch UniqueFilename="*virt-viewer-0.6.0-12.el7.x86_64.rpm" Silent="CRSNo" Reboot="RNo" Download="DManual">
      <Name>virt-viewer-0.6.0-12.el7.x86_64.rpm</Name>
      <Comments />
      <URL />
      <State>Enabled</State>
      <Files>
        <File>
          <Path>virt-viewer::x86_64</Path>
          <FileDate>0001-01-01T00:00:00.0000000</FileDate>
          <FileSize>0</FileSize>
          <Checksum>a9cbe660101210ee642e6dfc2d75f6c09232580cf3d8a859095c59c07d775acc</Checksum>
          <Version>0.6.0-12.el7</Version>
          <CommandID>e</CommandID>
          <Flags>P</Flags>
        </File>
      </Files>
      <Products>
        <ID>48327</ID>
      </Products>
      <Platforms>
        <ID>rhel7_x86_64</ID>
      </Platforms>
      <CustVars />
      <Cmds>
        <Cmd Type="shellscript">
          <Args>
            <Arg N="scriptcode" V="#!/bin/bash&#xA;&#xA;function updatepk()&#xA;{&#xA; if [ ! -z $1 ]; then&#xA;   if [ -e /var/run/yum.pid ];then &#xA;    exit 10  &#xA;   fi&#xA;   result=`yum -y update $1 2&gt;&amp;1` &#xA;   status=$? &#xA;   commandexist=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;yum: command not found&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$commandexist&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 8&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;    commandexist=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;yum: No such file or directory&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$commandexist&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 8&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   islock=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;lock /var/run/yum.pid&quot;`&#xA;   &#xA;   if [ &quot;$islock&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 10&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   islock=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;/var/run/yum.pid: another copy is running&quot;`&#xA;   &#xA;   if [ &quot;$islock&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 10&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;There was an error communicating with RHN&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;This system is not registered with RHN&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;    isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;No Repositories Available to Set Up&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;    isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;Error Class Code: 9 Error Class Info: Invalid System Credentials&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;    isscriptletfailed=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;error:&quot; | grep -E &quot;scriptlet failed, exit status 255&quot;`&#xA;    if [ &quot;$isscriptletfailed&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 6&#xA;   fi&#xA;   if [ $status -ne 0 ];then&#xA;     exit 7&#xA;   fi &#xA; fi&#xA;}&#xA;updatepk virt-viewer  &#xA;&#xA;exit 0" />
          </Args>
        </Cmd>
      </Cmds>
    </Patch>
    <Patch UniqueFilename="*virt-viewer-debuginfo-0.6.0-12.el7.x86_64.rpm" Silent="CRSNo" Reboot="RNo" Download="DManual">
      <Name>virt-viewer-debuginfo-0.6.0-12.el7.x86_64.rpm</Name>
      <Comments />
      <URL />
      <State>Enabled</State>
      <Files>
        <File>
          <Path>virt-viewer-debuginfo::x86_64</Path>
          <FileDate>0001-01-01T00:00:00.0000000</FileDate>
          <FileSize>0</FileSize>
          <Checksum>dfad72362aba946d8c3416e03c3a88bd2901581f590caa0282d9ffa9ed6a6aa1</Checksum>
          <Version>0.6.0-12.el7</Version>
          <CommandID>e</CommandID>
          <Flags>P</Flags>
        </File>
      </Files>
      <Products>
        <ID>55151</ID>
      </Products>
      <Platforms>
        <ID>rhel7_x86_64</ID>
      </Platforms>
      <CustVars />
      <Cmds>
        <Cmd Type="shellscript">
          <Args>
            <Arg N="scriptcode" V="#!/bin/bash&#xA;&#xA;function updatepk()&#xA;{&#xA; if [ ! -z $1 ]; then&#xA;   if [ -e /var/run/yum.pid ];then &#xA;    exit 10  &#xA;   fi&#xA;   result=`yum -y update $1 2&gt;&amp;1` &#xA;   status=$? &#xA;   commandexist=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;yum: command not found&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$commandexist&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 8&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;    commandexist=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;yum: No such file or directory&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$commandexist&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 8&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   islock=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;lock /var/run/yum.pid&quot;`&#xA;   &#xA;   if [ &quot;$islock&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 10&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   islock=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;/var/run/yum.pid: another copy is running&quot;`&#xA;   &#xA;   if [ &quot;$islock&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 10&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;There was an error communicating with RHN&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;   isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;This system is not registered with RHN&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;   &#xA;    isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;No Repositories Available to Set Up&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;    isnotconnected=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;Error Class Code: 9 Error Class Info: Invalid System Credentials&quot;`&#xA;   if [ &quot;$isnotconnected&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 9&#xA;   fi&#xA;    isscriptletfailed=`echo $result | grep -E &quot;error:&quot; | grep -E &quot;scriptlet failed, exit status 255&quot;`&#xA;    if [ &quot;$isscriptletfailed&quot; != &quot;&quot; ]; then&#xA;     exit 6&#xA;   fi&#xA;   if [ $status -ne 0 ];then&#xA;     exit 7&#xA;   fi &#xA; fi&#xA;}&#xA;updatepk virt-viewer-debuginfo  &#xA;&#xA;exit 0" />
          </Args>
        </Cmd>
      </Cmds>
    </Patch>
  </Patches>
  <PublishDate>2015-03-05T00:00:00.0000000</PublishDate>
  <Title>virt-viewer bug fix and enhancement update</Title>
  <Description>
        
The virt-viewer packages provide Virtual Machine Viewer, which is a lightweight interface for interacting with the graphical display of a virtualized guest.
The virt-viewer packages have been upgraded to upstream version 0.6.0, which provides a number of bug fixes and enhancements over the previous version, including significant improvements to multi-monitor support. (BZ#1109400)
Bugs: 
 Starting an application in full screen mode and then leaving full screen caused that the displayed window was too small. This bug has been fixed, and the window size is now reasonable after leaving full screen. (BZ#921332) 
 When connecting to a password-protected Virtual Network Computing (VNC) guest and a incorrect password was entered, the user was notified of the error, but was not presented with another password prompt to try again. With this fix, the password prompt is displayed again in the described situation. (BZ#1007306) 
 The "Automatically resize" check menu was ambiguous and not always working depending on protocol and capability of a guest. This update removes the "Automatically resize" menu, and the automatic guest resize is now enabled whenever the required conditions are met. (BZ#1007666) 
 Zooming in and out on a window in virt-viewer or remote-viewer could cause the guest display to be resized rather than simply scaling the local display. With this fix, the guest display is never resized in response to zooming in or out in the client. (BZ#1022404)
 Previously, connecting to a server with the "--fullscreen=auto-conf" option, leaving full screen and then opening another display led to the second display opening in full screen or incorrect resolution adjustment of the guest. With this update, the new display opens in window mode after leaving full screen as expected, and leaving and re-entering full screen mode now works as expected. (BZ#1022426, BZ#1096718) 
 Previously, when resizing a monitor, stale position information was used to align the monitors. Consequently, a display could unexpectedly change its position. To fix this bug, the current position of displays is always used to determine alignment, and displays no longer relocate unexpectedly when a window is resized. (BZ#1023253) 
 Due to failures not handled properly, the window showed the failed URL as the window title on a second attempt of a connection failure. With this update, the display window is closed upon connection failure and the title reset on each retry. (BZ#1024312) 
 When the server got disconnected, the nc utility did not end, leaving the client open. Consequently, the client did not disconnect when tunnelled over SSH on VM shutdown. This update replaces nc with socat, thus fixing the bug. (BZ#1030487) 
 When the agent terminated unexpectedly or was disconnected and reconnected again, virt-viewer did not update the information about windows geometry and the guest resolution was not changed accordingly. With this update, the function responsible for updating the displays geometry is called, thus fixing the bug. (BZ#1032971) 
Enhancements:
 With this update, when a connection failure occurs, a detailed reason in the error dialog is provided instead of a generic message. In addition, a more accurate message is shown when an authentication error occurs using TCP connection. The user can also cancel the dialog without any random message being displayed. (BZ#1115986, BZ#1142742) 
 The user is now allowed to customize the placement of VM windows in full screen mode and multi-monitor setups. (BZ#1129477) 
 The CONTROLLER_AUTO_DISPLAY_RES flag is no longer set automatically when using the Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization Manager portal. The client is opened in full screen mode only when the flag is set. (BZ#1149352)
Users of virt-viewer are advised to upgrade to these updated packages, which fix these bugs and add these enhancements.
        Note for remediation: Please disable the SELinux for RHEL 4/5 when repairing, or some rpm packages will fail to install.</Description>
  <Severity>5</Severity>
  <Vendor>Redhat</Vendor>
  <MoreInfoURL>https://access.redhat.com/errata/RHBA-2015:0295</MoreInfoURL>
  <FAQURL />
</Vulnerability>